M. Murat Ardag 🗘 🛅

Citizenship: Cypriot (EU), British Overseas & Turkish https://mmuratardag.github.io | mma@mmuratardag.net

ABOUT

I am a data scientist and a political psychologist. I specialize in psychometrics, psycholinguistics, cross-cultural research, and modeling subjectivity. My work almost always involves machine & deep learning, natural language processing, the general structural equation modeling framework, psychometric networks & social network analysis.

SKILLS

Data Science

Proficient with

Python: pandas, numpy, scikit-learn,

matplotlib, seaborn

R: tidverse, tidymodels, tidyflow, easystats, lavaan (and its ecosystem), psychometric networks (collection of packages), quanteda,

spacy

Familiar with:

Tensorflow-Keras, pytorch, prophet

Other

Proficient with

Git, Bash

Familiar with:

Postgres, MongoDB, AWS (EC2, RDS), Docker, Flask

EDUCATION

Data Science Bootcamp

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021 | Berlin, Germany

Ph.D. in Political Science

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018 | CvO Universität Oldenburg, Oldenburg, Germany

M.A. in Political Science

Oct 2008 - May 2012 | Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey

M.A. in International Relations.

Oct 2005 - Feb 2008 | Galatasaray University, Istanbul, Turkey

B.A. in International Relations

Oct 1999 - Nov 2004 | Istanbul Bilgi University, Istanbul, Turkey

SELECTED PROJECTS

Measuring Organizational Practices [GitHub Repo]

Natural language processing

Movie Recommender [GitHub Repo]

Unsupervised machine learning

Image Classification with Deep Learning [GitHub Repo]

Deep learning

Dockerized Data Pipeline [GitHub Repo]

Involves: MongoDB, ETL job (sentiment analysis), Postgres & Slackbot

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Jacobs University | Postdoctoral Fellow Feb 2020 - Nov 2020 | Bremen, Germany

- Worked as the lead data analyst in a third-party funded project (<u>Business Finland</u> & <u>Hofstede</u> <u>Insights</u>) developing a dictionary that measures organizational culture with <u>Hofstede's Multi-Focus</u> <u>Model</u>
 - using the R tidy ecosystem; the quanteda ecosystem (including spacyr), rJST & the easystats ecosystem

Bremen International School of Social Sciences

Affiliated Postdoctoral Fellow Since Feb 2019 | Bremen, Germany

> Conducting research, publishing academic papers, teaching methods classes

CvO Universität Oldenburg | (Interim-) Academic

Coordinator

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020 | Oldenburg, Germany

CvO Universität Oldenburg | Research Assistant

Lecturer

Jul 2015 – Jul 2018 | Oldenburg, Germany

LANGUAGES

Turkish (Native), English (Proficient), German (Intermediate)